# PENELOPE MAGAWAY

Digos City, Philippines · +63 961 000 1804 · +65 9641 3879 (WhatsApp)
penelope\_magaway@yahoo.com · github.com/PenelopeCM · tableau public/penelope magaway

A Google data analytics professional committed to pursuing a long-term career change as a data analyst. Good understanding and proficiency of platforms for effective data analyses, including SQL, Sheets, Excel, and Tableau. Offers a 10+ year track record demonstrating strong analytical and problem-solving skills, computer proficiency and ability to follow through with projects from inception to completion.

### **SKILLS**

- SQL
- Microsoft Excel
- Big Query
- Planning

- Tableau
- Google Sheets
- Data Analysis
- Research

#### **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS**

MICROSOFT EXCEL – DATA ANALYSIS WITH EXCEL PIVOT TABLES

December 2021, Udemy

**GOOGLE DATA ANALYTICS PROFESSIONAL** 

October 2021, Coursera

PROGRAMMING FOR EVERYBODY (GETTING STARTED WITH PYTHON)

June 2021, University of Michigan (Online)

**BS IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING** 

University of the Immaculate Conception, Philippines

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

SUPPORT ENGINEER, CEBU MICROELECTRONICS INC., PHILIPPINES

- Led a team of six to establish a new optical production line from zero output to 100% production mode; promoted to production section head.
- Resolved process abnormalities by collecting, summarizing, cleaning, and analyzing data to identify the root cause of the problem and presented findings to relevant stakeholders.

## OTHER EXPERIENCE

2015 - 2020

**SR. PERSONNEL PLANNING COORDINATOR,** FUGRO SINGAPORE MARINE PTE LTD, SINGAPORE

Supported 150+ offshore survey specialists in the APAC region; skills matched every team project assignment resulting in well-balanced teams, quality, and on-time job completion.

2007 - 2015

**DOCUMENT CONTROL SECRETARY, FUGRO SURVEY PTE LTD, SINGAPORE** 

Edit and proofread technical reports according to company business style.

2004 - 2007

PRODUCTION SECTION HEAD, CEBU MICROELECTRONICS INC., PHILIPPINES

Supervised overall production operations; analyzed manpower loading of a 30-man production team resulting in 100% on-time shipment.